[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
=Against The Current=
(Adapted from He Yanshan's novel, Orchid Fragrance Fate)
=Episode 27= (This drama does not correspond)
(to any real historical dynasty.)
(The systems, culture, attire and other dynastic elements have been adapted.)
The ceremony is complete.
Lead the way with lanterns.
Go forth to welcome the bride.
(Upholding the Virtue of Generations Past)
(Glorify the Family Name)
♪The wind blows past distant hills♪
♪The moon kisses the rising smoke♪
♪Whose oil lamp burns tonight?♪
♪Peace of heart in three places♪
Go to your husband's home.
Let obedience be your guiding principle.
Never forget to be solemn and respectful.
Be ever respectful
and ever mindful.
Do not disobey your parents-in-law.
♪Flowers bloom again by the fence♪
♪Snow falls white upon the eaves♪
Father.
Mother.
While I'm away,
please take good care of yourselves.
♪The journey home is always filled with joy and sorrow♪
♪People gather, then part♪
♪Regret is writing, "I hope this letter finds you well"♪
♪Yet watching their figures grow frail♪
♪In my hometown, leaves fall upon the gray roof tiles♪
♪Leaving only a small house behind♪
♪Flowers bloom again by the fence♪
♪Snow covers the eaves once more♪
The groom has arrived.
Please have the bride enter the bridal sedan.
The groom has arrived. Please have the bride enter the bridal sedan!
Get into the bridal sedan!
Please have the bride come out and enter the bridal sedan!
The groom has arrived!
Please have the bride enter the bridal sedan!
♪Say we'll meet again in our dreams♪
The groom has arrived.
Please have the bride enter the bridal sedan.
The groom has arrived. Please have the bride enter the bridal sedan.
(The Joyous Union of the Lin and Xu Families)
(Double Happiness)
(Lu Family Painting and Calligraphy Shop)
I pay my respects to you, Father and Mother.
Young...
By the Emperor's command,
I give my daughter to you as your wife.
May the two of you, from this day forward,
live together in perfect harmony,
and enjoy peaceful years together.
Do not fail to honor the Emperor's gracious intent,
nor cause your parents sorrow.
I will remember your counsel, Father.
I will never cause our elders sorrow
or disappoint His Majesty.
The auspicious hour has arrived. Please have the bride enter the bridal sedan.
Careful.
- Good! - Good!
(The Joyous Union of the Lin and Xu Families)
Steady the sedan.
Lift the sedan.
Raise the sedan.
Let's go!
Raise the sedan. Let's go!
(The Joyous Union of the Lin and Xu Families)
Make way!
Can't you see we're escorting a bride?
Don't make us miss the auspicious hour.
Make way!
We've been ordered to bring the good news to Scholar Han's home.
A wedding night
may be one of life's great occasions,
but throughout Jinling City,
men get married every day.
But to place first
in the provincial examination
is a distinction granted to one in ten thousand.
Exactly. One in ten thousand.
Clearly, placing first in the examination is the greater occasion.
Sir, we'd appreciate your help.
Please make way.
- Please make way, Sir. - Please make way, Sir.
What's going on?
The provincial examination was postponed after the late Emperor's death.
The results were only released today.
We deliberately avoided the area around the Confucius Temple,
but despite all our planning,
we never expected Scholar Han to pass,
much less place first.
The top provincial graduate, Scholar Han?
Yes, Scholar Han...
What are we going to do?
They're both major occasions. Who should give way to whom?
- Please make way, Sir. - Please make way, Sir.
We need to handle this carefully.
Placing first in Jiangnan is no ordinary distinction.
He may well become a Hanlin bachelor
and eventually enter the Grand Secretariat.
It's all your fault.
If you had worked harder and passed the examination,
we would've gone to the examination hall to see the results.
Then we'd know who placed first and where he lives.
How... how is this my fault?
Of course it's your fault.
Lanxiang, don't worry.
We've run into a procession bringing news to the top provincial graduate.
I hear his name is Han Liang,
and he lives nearby, too.
You could say you're neighbors.
Don't worry.
Don't be afraid, Lanxiang.
I'm really good with my slingshot now.
I won't let them disturb you.
The top provincial graduate, Scholar Han, is here!
Han.
Thank you.
Scholar Han.
He's so young.
He doesn't look bookish at all.
He has a promising future ahead of him.
We mustn't offend him. We mustn't.
I already have.
Congratulations on placing first in the provincial examination, Scholar Han.
I also studied at Qixia Academy,
so I know well that only after ten years of diligent study
could you earn a place on the honor roll today.
This is one of life's great joys,
and I shouldn't spoil the occasion.
But
a smooth bridal procession
is said to promise a smooth marriage.
So I ask you and your fellow scholars
to please make way.
I heard the bride was a maid.
I thought Commander Lin would say,
"The Emperor bestowed this marriage,
so I order you to make way."
Had I not been truly sincere,
I could never have obtained the Emperor's decree for this marriage.
So I hope, Scholar Han,
you'll consider the sincerity of my devotion
and help another man fulfill his wish.
♪Let the cold wind rage, let the wild rain fall♪
♪Let sorrow spill like shadows over all♪
♪Let beginnings fade as endings come to call♪
Thank you all
for taking the trouble to come and bring me the good news.
My home is rather cramped,
so I'm afraid I can't properly receive you there.
Scholar Zongbai
has already reserved a banquet
at Zuixian Restaurant.
Please join us for a modest drink
so we can celebrate together.
- All right. - All right.
Let's go.
Let's go celebrate Scholar Han's success.
- Come on, let's go celebrate! - Let's go celebrate!
- Congratulations, Scholar Han! - Congratulations, Scholar Han!
- Congratulations! - Congratulations!
What... Didn't you say you'd already offended him?
Didn't he make way for you right away?
He didn't do it for me.
Let's go.
Wait.
What was that about?
I have no idea.
All right, keep the music going.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- Congratulations! - Congratulations!
♪From this endless dream, there's no return at all♪
♪No page could hold the longing words can never show♪
Bride, it's time to step out of the sedan.
Let's not miss the auspicious hour.
Come.
Careful.
Bride and groom, please hold the red ribbon.
May peace bless every generation.
- Good! - Good!
May the family line continue,
with each generation surpassing the last.
♪From this endless dream, there's no return at all♪
♪Let the cold wind rage, let the wild rain fall♪
♪Let sorrow spill like shadows over all♪
♪Let love fall to pieces, let old anger burn away♪
♪Let the past die with yesterday♪
♪One last fire, one last cup of liquor♪
♪And silver moonlight to guide me through the night♪
First bow to Heaven and Earth.
- Good! - Good!
Second bow to your parents.
Now bow to each other.
- Good! - Good!
Lanxiang.
- What's going on? - Why haven't they performed the bow?
That's right.
What's happened?
Bride.
Come.
- Good! - Good!
Escort the newlyweds to the bridal chamber.
Good!
Let's have some fun with the newlyweds!
Have some fun with the newlyweds!
- Good! - Good!
Wash up.
Use the scale to lift the bridal veil and reveal the bride's beautiful face.
- Good! - Good!
What's the rush?
It's Jinqi who gets to lift the veil, not you.
Tomorrow I'll tell Second Madam Lin
it's time to find Jincen a wife.
I don't want one!
Groom, please lift the bridal veil.
- Good! - Good!
(Lin)
Today, we join our lives as one.
May we be of one heart and grow old together.
- Good! - Good!
You've gone too far.
No...
Why did she hit him?
I don't get it.
What's going on?
What happened?
What's happening up front?
We've seen the couple share the ceremonial meal.
Let's go have a drink.
Shaohui.
If you want a drink, go find Liu.
I still want to see what happens next.
Everyone, at tonight's wedding banquet,
there's fine liquor bestowed by His Majesty.
If you don't go now, you'll miss out.
Come on, let's go drink the fine liquor.
Let's go.
- Come on, let's go drink. - Everyone, let's go.
Come on, let's go drink.
Right.
You may all leave.
Go have a drink.
Let's go.
All of you,
keep your mouths shut about this.
- Yes. - Yes.
I should have come to ask
for your parents' consent
before discussing marriage with you.
I was at fault.
Please forgive me, my lady.
♪The golden sunset♪
♪Sketches my thoughts♪
♪All things fall silent♪
♪Fearing to disturb this moment♪
♪My restless heart seeks a place to anchor♪
♪Yet I cannot stop searching♪
♪I wonder if the past has ever been heard♪
♪Yesterday's brush and ink♪
♪Lightly traced cause and effect♪
(Lin)
♪Half a lifetime of longing♪
♪Returns to this moment♪
If you're hungry...
♪If the image isn't real, what does it matter?♪
♪I still remember your name♪
Yuchan, Gantang, and the others
are waiting outside.
Whatever you want to eat
or need,
just tell them anytime.
This is your home now.
Make yourself comfortable.
♪I no longer blame the moon♪
♪For withholding its light♪
♪I only pray that those I've known♪
I'll go outside
and see to the guests.
I'll be back a little later.
♪And leave the grass and trees covered in frost♪
♪I only wish that where the lights grow dim♪
♪You and I will walk there together♪
(Cry as hard as you can.)
(Let it all out.)
(Once we're done crying, let's live our lives well.)
♪Returns to this moment♪
Live with all your might.
Live as hard as you can.
Live like wild grass,
without a care in the world.
From now on,
(our days will know only spring,)
(never winter.)
(Let's live on without a care.)
♪No longer let the world's wind and snow fall♪
♪And leave the grass and trees covered in frost♪
♪I only wish that where the lights grow dim♪
♪You and I will walk there together♪
♪I no longer search through old dreams♪
♪Leaving them buried deep within the years♪
♪I only long to journey through the night together♪
♪Toward where my heart leads♪
♪I no longer lament that fate is hard to foresee♪
♪Accepting the unexpected as ordinary♪
♪I only wish the road behind us would fade like mist♪
♪And we would share the road home♪
Good for her!
He deserved it.
That wretched boy deserved it.
Is everything you just said true?
Young Madam had no idea
that Young Master wanted to marry her?
If you don't believe me,
you can send someone
to ask Madam Tao, the official matchmaker.
Uncle Xu and Aunt Xu
almost arranged her marriage
to the Han family next door.
Young Madam certainly has a fierce temper.
Even if Young Master forced her into this marriage,
a bride still shouldn't hit her groom.
That wretched boy went looking for a beating.
He even went to all that trouble
to obtain an imperial decree just to get himself beaten.
He deserved it.
You! This is all your fault!
You didn't try to talk Young Master out of it!
Mother, be reasonable!
Please be reasonable!
Young...
Is Young Master someone who listens to advice?
Even so, you should've tried to talk him out of it!
Enough.
Jiugao isn't the one who deserves a beating.
Get out of here.
Go back to the banquet
and attend to the guests.
So we're just letting this go?
If we don't,
am I supposed to help that wretched boy
by slapping the bride?
Haven't we made enough of a spectacle
of the Lin family already?
With that wretched boy around,
I think Jinling City
will have enough to laugh about for the next three to five years.
First Madam, it's a joyous occasion.
You can't hit him anymore. You can't!
I'm not hitting my son.
Surely you don't expect me
to greet the guests with a feather duster in my hand?
I'm getting senile.
That rotten boy.
He's been the only one happy
about this marriage from beginning to end,
yet he insists
that all of us smile along with him.
First Madam, you're worrying too much.
There are people who are genuinely happy for Young Master.
Of course they're genuinely happy
when there's a spectacle to enjoy.
Come. A toast to everyone.
Congratulations!
What took you so long?
Eat and drink your fill.
Good liquor.
See to the guests.
Eat and drink your fill!
Come, eat and drink your fill.
Let me take a look.
Did she break the skin?
Want me to rub it for you?
You only know
how to act fierce around us.
The moment you see your wife, you turn into a coward.
Jinqi,
you're in for a rough night.
Bitterness first, and sweetness later.
After hardship comes happiness.
Then let's drink to bitterness first, sweetness later,
and happiness after hardship.
All right.
Everyone,
let's raise a toast to the groom together.
- Good! - Good!
- Bitterness first, sweetness later. - Bitterness first, sweetness later.
- After hardship comes happiness. - After hardship comes happiness.
Young Madam,
it's really not proper to spend your wedding night in the side chamber.
You should return to the bedroom.
You both saw
what I did earlier.
It would be even less appropriate for me to stay there.
I was scared to death.
I was afraid you and Young Master would start fighting.
I didn't expect Young Master to be so good-tempered.
He acted as though nothing had happened
and went off to drink.
Mind your manners.
She is Young Madam.
Yes.
Young Madam.
My dear Young Madam,
just sit still.
I know you mean well,
but things are different now.
If anyone sees you doing this,
they'll get scolded.
Are we still friends?
My dear Young Madam,
of course we are.
As long as you don't take my work
away from me.
To be selfish for a moment,
I'm truly happy today.
Back then,
I was driven out of Zhichun Hall
and married off to a fool.
Now,
you're the Young Madam of Zhichun Hall.
From now on,
I won't have to fear that the new Young Madam will dislike me
and drive me out of Zhichun Hall again.
- Young Master. - Young Master.
You may all leave.
Let's go.
Before you left Zhichun Hall,
I already had feelings for you.
I know
you don't feel the same way about me.
To become your husband,
I've thought about it for a long time
and done a great deal.
But you
had no time to prepare
before suddenly becoming my wife.
I completely understand
why you're upset and resistant.
If I were in your place
and someone had schemed and manipulated me like this,
I'd want to kill them, too.
I'll give you time
to accept me.
I'll do everything I can
to make you fall for me, too.
But in this lifetime,
you,
Xu Lanxiang,
can only be
my wife.
Lin Jinqi!
What are you doing?
Put me down, Lin Jinqi!
Lin Jinqi!
What are you doing?
♪I'd spend every dawn and dusk to see it through♪
Lin Jinqi!
Put me down!
What are you doing? Put me down!
Lin Jinqi!
What are you trying to do?
From this day forward,
we are husband and wife,
and we'll share both fortune and hardship.
But
you'll enjoy the good fortune first,
and I'll bear the hardship first.
If it becomes more than I can bear,
then there's nothing I can do about it.
Tonight,
you'll sleep in the bedroom.
I'll sleep in the side chamber.
=Against the Current= (Next Episode's Preview)
A mother can't control her grown son.
Try to look on the bright side.
Jiugao
just doesn't want to marry.
At least
he hasn't brought some unreliable person into the family
to stand before you every day and make your life miserable.
First Madam is busy,
so I won't go in.
I'm fine now.
Don't let it weigh on you.
Don't.
Lanxiang! Lan...
All right.
♪Spring slips from the branches once more♪
♪Flowers bloom unseen, as they have before♪
♪All the joys and sorrows come and go♪
♪While loss leaves winter in the heart♪
♪Though all the world may fade♪
♪Time rolls on as countless lives rush by♪
♪Night winds wander through the halls of long ago♪
♪No page could hold the longing words can never show♪
♪Every joy and sorrow in this fleeting life♪
♪Fades into the past as new wounds rise♪
♪While whispers of perfume linger beneath the eaves♪
♪Let the cold wind rage, let the wild rain fall♪
♪Let sorrow spill like shadows over all♪
♪Let love fall to pieces, let old anger burn away♪
♪Let the past die with yesterday♪
♪One last fire, one last cup of wine♪
♪And silver moonlight to guide me through the night♪
♪Let beginnings fade as endings come to call♪
♪From this endless dream, there's no return at all♪
♪Let the cold wind rage, let the wild rain fall♪
♪Let sorrow spill like shadows over all♪
♪Let love fall to pieces, let old anger burn away♪
♪Let the past die with yesterday♪
♪One last fire, one last cup of wine♪
♪And silver moonlight to guide me through the night♪
♪Let beginnings fade as endings come to call♪
♪From this endless dream, there's no return at all♪